Guide to the Charlotte Painter Papers, 1955-1992
Department of Special Collections
- Series II: Material Relating to her Published Works
  - Gifts of Age (Chronicle Books, 1985): (Box 2, Folder 19)
    - Publication Correspondence (by author)
      - Beverlye Human and Louise Latham to Martha Casselman (12/87)
      - Beverlye Human and Louise Latham to Martha Casselman (5/87)
      - Kathi Wheater (n.d.)
      - Martha Casselman to Jack Jensen (6/89)
      - Evelyn Renold to Miriam Altshuler (10/89)
      - Martha Casselman (12/89)
      - Miriam Altshuler (12/89)
      - Martha Casselman to Jack Jensen (3/90)
      - Bill to Marti [Martha Casselman] (3/90)
      - Carla Charlton to Martha Casselman (4/92)
  - Gifts of Age: (Box 2, Folder 20)
    - Personal Correspondence (by author)
      - Elizabeth Janeway (6/85)
      - Diane Johnson (2/86)
      - [Ayn] Thorne (6/86)
      - Katherine Hunt (6/86)
  - Gifts of Age: Reviews (Box 2, Folder 21)
  - Gifts of Age: Reviews (cont'd) (Box 2, Folder 22)
  - Gifts of Age: Royalty Statements (Box 2, Folder 23)
  - Miscellaneous papers on the publication of Gifts of Age: A Book of Days (Box 2, Folder 24)
  - Gifts of Age: Correspondence with biographical subjects_& Permission Statements (Box 2, Folder 25)
  - Gifts of Age: Painter's Notes (Box 2, Folder 26)
  - Gifts of Age: Painter's Notes (cont'd) (Box 2, Folder 27)
  - Gifts of Age: Photographs of Biographical Subjects, Note: Galley proof for Gifts of Age may be found in Box 8 (OS) (Box 2, Folder 28)
- Series III: Material Pertaining to Stories, Proposed Works, Projects and Miscellaneous Correspondence
  - Short Stories and Articles and Related Correspondence (by author) (1955-1972): (Box 3, Folder 1)
    - Henry Volkening (4/63)
    - Barbara Blakemore to Diarmuid Russell (8/63)
    - Peter Wyden (6/65)
    - Julie Chametzky (9/68)
  - Short Stories (continued) (1983-1987)Publication Correspondence (by author): (Box 3, Folder 2)
    - PEN Syndicated Fiction Project (1983), (5 items)
    - PEN Syndicated Fiction Project (1987), (1 itme)
  - Proposed work: Revelations Diary (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Wilderness Women Project (1979): (Box 3, Folder 4)
    - Painter's notes
  - Wilderness Women Project: (Box 3, Folder 5)
    - Correspondence and Painter's Text
  - Reviews and Speaking Engagements by C. Painter (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Miscellaneous Correspondence - Hugh Nissenson: (Box 3, Folder 7)
    - (1978-1979), 3 items
  - Miscellaneous Correspondence: (Box 3, Folder 8)
    - Klaus (?) (12/78)
    - Anthony Friendson (7/79)
    - C. Painter to Lynn Nesbit (2/80)
    - Lynn Nesbit (3/80)
    - Raymond Carver (8/83)
    - Unknown (n.d.)
- Series IV: Audio Tapes, Manuscripts and Galley Proofs
  - Audio Tapes: Interviews for Gifts of Age, Interviewee, Tape # (Box 4, Folder 1)
    - Albrier, Frances M. (Othertype 17)
    - Aroldo, Josephine E. (Othertype 3)
    - Baez, Joan Sr. (Othertype 13)
    - Casper, Ursula H. (Othertype 16)
    - Davies, Louise M. (Othertype 8)
    - Fisher, Mary F.K. (Othertype 9)
    - Fong Yu, Alice (Othertype 5)
    - Gardener, Margaret B. (Othertype 10)
    - Hayes, Margaret C. (Othertype 7)
    - Kehoe, Monika (Othertype 2)
    - Lawrence, Eleanor M. (Othertype 3)
    - Lewis, Lucy (Othertype 3)
    - Lovejoy, Marie L. (Othertype 10, 11)
    - Lowdermilk, Inez M. (Othertype 17)
    - Maybeck, Jacomena (Othertype 1)
    - Murdock, Margaret (Othertype 4)
    - Obata, Haruko (Othertype 19)
    - Patri, Stella N. (Othertype 12)
    - Pierce, Cecil (Othertype 6)
    - Pinska, Klarna (Othertype 11, 12)
    - Snyder, Alice L. (Othertype 1, 2)
    - Walsh, Virginia (Othertype 18)
    - Wheelwright, Jane H. (Othertype 14, 15)
  - Radio Interview:
    - Charlotte Painter (Othertype 20)
  - Video Cassette: Interview with C. Painter and Mary Jane Moffat (1984?) (Box 4, Folder 2)
- Series V: Manuscripts and Galley Proofs
  - Manuscript: Who Made the Lamb (1964) (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - Manuscript: Confessions from the Malaga Madhouse (1971) (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - Manuscript: Seeing Things (1975) (Box 7, Folder 1)
  - Galley Proof: Seeing Things (1975) (Box 8, Folder 1)
  - Retouched Galley Proof: Seeing Things (1975) (Box 8, Folder 2)
  - Printer's Proof: Confessions from the Malaga Madhouse (Box 9, Folder 1)
  - Printer's Proof: Seeing Things (Box 9, Folder 2)
  - Printer's Proof: Seeing Things (Box 9, Folder 3)
  - Galley Proof: Gifts of Age (1985) (Box 10, Folder 1)
  - Galley Proof: Gifts of Age Daybook (1988) (Box 10, Folder 2)
  - Manuscript: The Heron (play) (Box 10, Folder 3)
  - Mediterranean Review (Fall 1970-Winter 1973) (Box 11, Folder 1)
  - Place: Rogues Gallery ( 1973,V.2:2) (Box 11, Folder 2)
  - The Nation ( January 24, 1972,V.214:4) (Box 11, Folder 3)
  - Redbook ( October 1963,V.121:6) (Box 11, Folder 4)
  - The New Yorker (February 5, 1955) (Box 11, Folder 5)